Finding Aid for the Julius Christian Jacobsen
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
The William Inge Collection
1936-1959
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0753
.21 linear feet
Biography/History
Julius Christian Jacobsen (1885-1960) was born in Denmark and immigrated to the United States with his family. He worked, for over 12 years in Colombia, South America with companies mining gold and platinum. The companies where he worked were: Compania Minera Choco Pacifico, and Pato Consolidated Gold Dredging, Limited. The letters describe working conditions and wages in Colombia, South America. They describe the rainy season and the floods, with their affect on their equipment. He mentions World War II and its possible impact on them.
Scope and Contents
He was married and had several children. The majority of the letters were written to his sons, Eric and Jonis. The letters describe some activities of his family who remained in the United States while he worked in South America. There are several business letters from Banco De La Republica to Mrs. Jacobsen; a letter to his son Jonis from Pato Consolidated Gold Dredging, Limited, Colombia, South America; and a letter from Schwarz to F. D. Bradbury.
This collection is .21 linear feet, containing 12 file folders. It contains correspondence, some handwritten. The collection has two series: Series I, Outgoing Correspondence; Series II, Miscellaneous Business Correspondence.
- Series I – Outgoing Correspondence
  - to son Eric, March 17, 1936 (Folder 1)
  - to son Eric, May 24, 1936 (Folder 1)
  - to son Eric, October 18, 1936 (Folder 1)
  - to son Eric, January 19, 1937 (Folder 2)
  - to son Eric, March 23, 1937 (Folder 2)
  - to son Eric, September 27, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - to son Jonis, December 14, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - to son Jonis, December 18, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - to son Eric, February 8, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - to son Jonis, May 2, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - to son Eric, May 2, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - to son Jonis, May 12, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - to son Eric, January 28, 1940 (Folder 5)
  - to son Eric, January 9, 1941 (Folder 6)
  - to Eric and Lorraine, September 8, 1945 (Folder 7)
  - to Eric and Lorraine, February 3, 1948 (Folder 8)
  - Christmas Cards, 1936, 1940 (Folder 9)
- Series II – Miscellaneous Business Correspondence
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, September 18, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, September 30, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, October 16, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, November 17, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, November 18, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Mrs. Jacobsen, November 24, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - letter to Jonis, October 7, 1938 (Folder 11)
  - from Schwarz to F. T. Bradbury, April 5, 1959 (Folder 12)